firearmsoutletcanada.com 2018-12-23

# Privacy Policy

Firearms Outlet Canada is dedicated to maintaining the security, confidentiality, and accuracy of your personal information. As part of this commitment, our actions are governed by our privacy policy as related to the collection, use and disclosure of personal information. Our privacy policy is established according to the standards and values set by the Canadian Standards Association’s Model Code for the Protection of Personal Information and our actions with regards to collecting, using, and disclosing personal information in the course of commercial activities are subject to “The Protection of Personal Information and Electronic Documents Act” (PIPEDA).

 **1\. Introduction**

The responsibility for maintaining and protecting your personal information is on us, within the bounds of our control. Individuals have been designated who are responsible for compliance with our privacy policy.

 **2\. Identifying Purposes**

We collect, use and disclose personal information to provide you with the products and/or services requested and to enhance your experience by offering you additional products and services we believe may be of interest to you. The purposes for which personal information is collected will be identified at or before the time of collection. In certain circumstances, the purposes for which information is collected may be clear and consent may be implied, such as where your name, address and payment information is provided as part of the order process.

 **3\. Consent**

Knowledge and consent are required for the collection, use or disclosure of personal information except where required or permitted by law. Providing us with your personal information is always your choice. However, failure to provide certain information may limit our ability to render you the products or services requested. You will not be required to consent to the use, collection, or disclosure of information as a condition to the supply of a product or service, except where required in order to supply a product or service.

 **4\. Limiting Collection**

The personal information collected by us will be limited to those details deemed necessary for the purposes identified by us. With your consent, personal information may be collected from you in person, over the telephone or by corresponding with you via mail, facsimile, or the Internet.

 **5\. Limiting Use, Disclosure and Retention**

Use and disclosure of personal information will be limited to the purpose or purposes for which it was collected unless otherwise consented by you, or when it is required and/or permitted by law. Retention of personal information will be limited to the period of time required to fulfill the purpose for which it was collected, or as may be required by law.

 **6\. Accuracy**

Accuracy, completion, and integrity of personal information will be maintained as is necessary to fulfill the purposes for which it is to be used.

 **7\. Safeguarding Customer Information**

Security measures appropriate to the sensitivity level of the information are in place to protect your personal information. All reasonable precautions to protect your personal information from any loss, unauthorized use, access, or disclosure will be taken. 

**8\. Openness**

Information about our policies and practices with respect to the management of your personal information will be made available to you.

 **9\. Customer Access**

Upon request, you will be informed of the existence, use and disclosure of your personal information and will be given access to it. The accuracy, integrity, and completeness of your personal information may be verified upon request, and amendments made, if appropriate. In certain circumstances, however, as permitted by law, certain information will not be disclosed to you. For example, information may not be disclosed relating to you if other individuals are referenced or if there are legal, security or commercial proprietary restrictions.

 **10\. Handling Customer Complaints and Suggestions**

Questions and/or enquiries with respect to our privacy policy and/or our practices may be directed to: info@firearmsoutletcanada.com.

Additional Information

 **Cookies**

A cookie is a small computer file or piece of information that may be stored in your computer’s hard drive when you visit our websites. Cookies may be used to improve our website’s functionality and, in some cases, provide visitors with a customized online experience.  
Cookies are widely used and most web browsers are configured to accept cookies automatically. Your Internet browser settings may be changed to prevent the acceptance of cookies or to notify the receipt of cookies so that its acceptance may be declined. Please note, however, if you disable cookies, you may not experience optimal performance of our website.

 **Other Websites**

Links to third party sites may be present within our website that are not governed by this privacy policy. Although we strive to only link to sites with high privacy standards, our privacy policy will not apply outside of our website. We are not responsible for the privacy practices employed by third party websites. It is recommended that you examine the privacy policies of those sites to learn how your information may be collected, use, shared, and disclosed.
